BASIL MEER

UI/UX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

♠	Lahore, Punjab
C	+92 336 412 4066
	hello@basilmeer.com
in	basilmeer
()	basilmeer

>EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN COMP. SCI.

Virtual University, Lahore 2018 - 2021

F.SC. PRE-ENGINEERING

KIPS College, Lahore 2013 - 2015

MATRICULATION

British Grammar School, Lahore 2011 - 2013

> SKILLS

//TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SASS
- Javascript
- Typescript
- jQuery
- Bootstrap 3 & 4
- Webpack
- Babel
- React.js
- Redux
- Linux
- Node
- Express
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Git
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- PHP
- Laravel
- WordPress
- Responsive Web Design
- Logo Design

> PROFILE

I am an autodidact with a background in Graphics Design, Web Design and Front-End Development. I am currently in the process of learning Node, React and Express through freelancing opportunities and personal projects while studying modern practices and standards.

I was one of the original Co-Founders, Interim C.T.O. and designer-turned-developer at Hobuddies (Pvt) Ltd., an interest-based speed-networking social media platform where I worked on its web and mobile platforms, spent 6 months at Engro Fertilizers developing and deploying a custom-tailored B2B solution on-site. I strictly imposed Agile and Scrum, drafted a Git branching model for the team to follow and lead the front-end development on all platforms.

I am currently working as the UI/UX Designer for Veteranlogix where my responsibilities include designing, maintaining and coding user interfaces, doing hotfixes to the production server, managing projects via Git, improving the codebase, implementing new features and acting as a supervisor on certain matters.

> PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VETERANLOGIX

UI/UX Designer & Developer Lahore, Pakistan | May 2018 - Present

Veteranlogix is a software-development agency that provides optimal digital and web solutions.

My responsibilities as the team's UI/UX Designer include:

- Overseeing development and making sure good practices followed
- Helping the team understand how to use Git to keep the work flow unobtrusive
- Active as a supervisor and lead on issues aside from design and front-end development
- Streamlining the tasks given and improving productivity using various team collaboration tools

BASIL MEER

UI/UX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER



> SKILLS

//PROFESSIONAL

- Graphic Design
- Web Design
- Brand Identity
- Team Management
- Project Management
- Research & Development
- Quick Adaption
- Self-Teaching
- Team Player

//IANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Urdu (Native)

Javascript

//TECHNICAL

jQuery
Node
Express
React.js
Redux
Webpack
MongoDB
MySQL

>PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Helping teammates understand new concepts by providing resources and explaining concepts
- Implementing new features while ensuring a seamless integration
- Doing hotfixes to the production server as a dedicated support
- Assisting the team in creating and maintaining user interfaces
- Writing clean, re-usable markup and code with a component-based approach
- Doing user experience reviews for all existing and ongoing projects
- Handling all graphics-related jobs including logo design, print design and web design

HOBUDDIES (PVT) LTD.

Interim C.T.O. & Front-End Developer | Lahore, Pakistan | March 2017 - 2018

Hobuddies is a speed-networking social media platform that matches like-minded people based on their interests and personality.

My tasks primarily involved managing the team, doing front-end development and graphics design. As such, mycontributions to the team included:

- Improving the team's productivity through the introduction of a practical Git branching model and adopting Agile; 20% improvement was overall observed
- Communicating with the clientele to design intuitive layouts according to their needs and implement their provided feedback
- Streamlining the workflow using Git, introducing Trello and Scrumming to ensure more productivity
- Proposing a seamless design for the apps and prototyping it in Ionic
- Handling all graphics-related jobs which included designing logos, wallpapers, icons, banners, standees, social media images and posters

BASIL MEER

UI/UX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

♣ Lahore, Punjab
♣ +92 336 412 4066
♠ hello@basilmeer.com
in basilmeer
♠ basilmeer

>SKILLS

//TECHNICAL

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Git

Linux

Bootstrap 3 & 4

SASS

PHP

Laravel

>INTERESTS

- Video Games
- e-Sports
- Reading
- Movies
- Writing
- Motor Bikes
- Mechanical Keyboards

> PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INNOVERSETECH

Graphics Designer | Lahore, Pakistan | April 2016 - March 2017

InnoverseTech was a Lahore-based software house that provided B2B digital solutions ranging from websites, management systems to SEO and website administration.

During my tenure, my responsibilities included:

- Designing graphics for the clientele that varied between digital and print media
- Handling and creating all graphical resources for the assigned projects
- Working alongside the developers to ensure a good user interface and users experience
- Writing markup and functionality for websites

SELF-EMPLOYED (FREELANCING)

Web Designer & Video Editor | Lahore, Pakistan | December 2016 - 2017

I occasionally worked as a freelance designer and video editor for the local clientele. Some of the tasks then included:

- Converting PSDs to responsive HTML
- Designing web pages for marketing purposes
- Doing animations and video edits using Adobe After Effects and Adobe Premiere